Finding Aid for Marion L. Burton Papers 1895-1925
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  - Commencement and miscellaneous (Box 23)
American Social Hygiene Association.
1924-1925 [17-14]
Anti-Saloon League of America.
1922 [12-37]
Babst, Earl D. 1870-1967.
1921 [1-9]; 1922 [8-27]; 1923 [9-14]
Balfour, Arthur James,1848-1930.
1922 [5-10]
Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.
1921 [1-11]; 1921-1922 [5-11]; 1922-1923 [9-17]; 1922 [12-15]; 1923-1924 [13-14]; 1924-1925 [17-18]
Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.
1921 [1-13]; 1921-1922 [5-13]; 1922-1923 [9-19]; 1923-1924 [13-15]; 1924-1925 [17-19]
Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.
1920 [1-16]; 1922 [5-18]; 1923 [9-23]
Chapin, Roy Dikeman, 1880-1936.
1920-1921 [1-25]; 1921-1922 [5-27]
Clancy, Robert Henry, 1882-
1923 [10-1]; 1924 [14-1]; 1924 [17-31]
Clements, William Lawrence, 1861-1934.
1921 [1-27]; 1922 [5-28]; 1922 [5-29]; 1922-1923 [10-2]; 1923-1924 [14-2]; 1924-1925 [17-32]
Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn, 1855-1944.
1921 [1-30]; 1922 [5-33]; 1922-1923 [10-6]; 1923-1924 [14-9]; 1924-1925 [18-3]
Coolidge, Calvin, Pres. U.S., 1872-1933.
1921 [5-30]; 1924 [14-7]
Couzens, James Joseph, 1872-1936.
1921 [4-16]; 1922 [5-30]; 1923 [10-5]; 1923-1924 [14-10]; 1924-1925 [18-2]
Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929.
1921 [2-1]; 1921 [5-37]; 1923 [10-10]; 1924 [14-14]
Douglas, Lloyd Cassel, 1877-1951.
1920 [2-2]
DuBois, William Edward Burghardt, 1868-1963.
1923 [10-13]
Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.
1921 [1-17]; 1921 [1-20]; 1921 [2-4]; 1922 [6-3]; 1922-1923 [10-15]; 1922 [12-4]; 1923-1924 [14-19]; 1924-1925 [18-10]; 1923-1924 [17-5]
Ferris, Woodbridge Nathan, 1853-1928.
1924 [14-21]; 1925 [18-12]
Fletcher, Frank Ward, 1853-1922.
1921 [2-10]
Ford, Edsel Bryant, 1893-1943.
1924 [14-22]
Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.
1924 [14-22]; 1924 [18-12]
Frost, Robert Lee, 1874-1963.
1921-1922 [6-10]; 1922-1923 [10-18]; 1923-1924 [14-22]; 1924-1925 [18-13]
Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924.
1921-1922 [6-11]
Groesbeck, Alexander J., 1873-1953.
1921 [4-31]; 1921 [6-14]; 1922-1923 [10-24]; 1923 [12-4]; 1923-1924 [14-27]; 1924-1925 [18-18]
Harding, Warren Gamaliel, Pres. U.S., 1865-1923.
1922 [6-17]
Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.
1922 [10-25]
Hinsdale, Wilbert Bartlett, 1851-1944.
1921 [2-21]; 1921-1922 [6-21]; 1920-1921 [6-22]
Hoover, Herbert Clark, Pres. U.S., 1874-1964.
1921 [6-23]; 1923 [10-32]
Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.
1921 [2-26]; 1921 [6-24; 1923 [11-1]; 1924 [15-1]
Hutchins, Harry Burns, 1847-1930.
1921 [2-28]
International Anti-Narcotic League.
1923 [11-3]
International Narcotic Education Association.
1924 [15-3]
Lloyd, Alfred Henry, 1864-1927.
1921 [3-7]; 1921-1922 [7-7]; 1922-1923 [11-21]; 1923-1924 [15-15]; 1924-1925 [18-40]
Lorch, Emil, 1870-1963.
1921 [3-6]; 1921-1922 [7-8]; 1923 [11-19]; 1923 [15-14]
Michener, Earl Cory, 1876-1957.
1924 [15-19]; 1925 [18-43]
Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.
1921 [3-26]; 1921 [4-5]; 1921-1922 [7-17]; 1922-1923 [11-29]; 1923-1924 [15-23]; 1924-1925 [18-45]
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.
1922 [7-18]
National Council of Prevention of War.
1922 [11-30]; 1923 [15-24]; 1925 [18-47]
National Movement for Law Enforcement.
1924 [16-13]
Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.
1922 [11-30]
Non-Partisan Association for the League of Nations.
1922 [9-9]
Osborn, Chase Salmon, 1860-1949.
1920-1921 [3-31]; 1921-1922 [7-22]; 1922-1923 [11-33]; 1923-1924 [15-29]; 1924-1925 [18-48]
Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.
1922-1923 [12-6]
Rackham, Horace H., 1858-1933.
1923 [16-3]
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-
1921 [4-5]; 1922 [8-6]; 1922-1923 [12-12]; 1923-1924 [16-6]; 1924-1925 [18-53]
Sink, Charles Albert, 1879-
1920-1921 [4-12]; 1921-1922 [8-13]; 1922-1923 [12-18]
Sleeper, Albert E., 1862-1934.
1920 [4-11]
Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.
1922 [12-26]
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951.
1922 [8-27]; 1923 [12-31]; 1923-1924 [17-1]
Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1898-
1921 [4-28]
Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.
1920-1921 [4-29]; 1923 [17-1]
Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
1921-1922 [9-8]; 1922-1923 [13-5]; 1923-1924 [17-13]
Selective Subject Index to Correspondence
The subject index is arranged in four broad categories: Administration, Building Program, Academic Units, and Miscellaneous. Entries under a subject include name of correspondent, box and folder number, and date. When no date is given, the entire folder is relevant except for a few cases where there may be only an occasional useful item. Most of the correspondents included in the index are university regents or top level administrators.
I. Administration Assistant to president added to staff: Hutchins (2-28); S.W.Smith (4-14, passim; 4-15, passim) By-laws re-written: Hubbard (2-25; 6-26) Dean of Students position established: Status and jurisdiction: Bursley (5-21, 10/21/21) Student Employment Bureau: Evans (2-8) Student Loan Fund: Effinger (6-3, Sept.'21) Departmental governance: E.E. Day (5-36) M.E. Cooley (5-33, 1/9/22 and 3/21/22) Departmental additions and changes in status: Addition of social work curriculum: Effinger (2-4, passim) Murfin (3-26, 10/8/20) Social workers (4-16) Engineering Research Laboratory: Hanchett (2-17, 4/29/20, 5/10/20) Library Science, Plans to establish department: Bishop (9-20, 12/30/22) Music School, Plans to incorporate in U-M: Gore (10-22) Physical education: Murfin (3-26, reports) Pomeroy (4-1, on women's needs) Faculty salary policy: Day (18-7, 8/29/24, 10/16/24, re: his appointment to salary policy committee) Effinger (18-10, 8/29/24, his salary policy recommendations) Hubbard (18-27, 8/28/24, MLB letter to regents on salary policy changes needed in '24-'25) Regental committee structure re-organized: Murfin (15-23, 3/8 and 3/10/24) Student discipline: General: M.E.Cooley (5-33, 3/25/22; 10-6, 7/3/22) Hubbard (6-26, 6/1/22) Ward (8-32, 1/20/22) Beal (9-19, 5/29/23; 13-15, 10/2/23) Autos on campus: Murfin (11-29, 11/9/22, 11/20/22, 5/31, 6/11 and 6/12/22; 15-23, 7/31, 8/8, 8/29, and 10/22/23) Bursley (13-21, 8/2/23) S.W.Smith (16-14, 10/4/23) Decision-making and handling of: Lloyd (15-15, passim) Regents (16-4, 5/25/23) Drinking at football games: Murfin (15-23, 10/23/23) Expulsion and re-instatement of four Engineering students: Bursley (13-21, 12/7 and 12/17/23) M.E.Cooley (14-9, 12/24 and 12/29/23) Effinger (14-19, 10/19 and 12/7/23) Honor system for exams: M.E.Cooley (14-9, 3/7/24) Effinger (14-19, 9/12/24)
II. Building Program Acquisition of land: Murfin (11-29, July '22) S. W. Smith (12-20, 5/3/23) Christensen (13-29, 1/28/24) Building plans: Committee of Five (5-31; 14-5; 17-35, minutes) Clements (1-27; 5-29; 10-2, passim) Kahn (3-1; 6-35; 11-10; 15-8; 18-34) Lorch (3-6) Shepard (4-10; 8-12; 12-17, 1/5/23; 16-12) S. W. Smith (4-14, passim) M.E. Cooley (10-6, 7/1/22) Nelson (15-26, 5/28/24, plans for a university theater) Pitkin (16-2, landscaping) Clements Library: Beal (9-19, 11/6/22 ff.) Bishop (9-20, 9/29/22) Clements (14-2) Clements Library (17-33, financial reports and operation of library) Contracting and costs: Legislative requests (3-5) Michigan State Budget Commission (3-20) S. W. Smith (8-15, 7/15 and 7/29/21, 12/2/21, 2/8/22; 12-20, 3/2/23) Gore (6-12, passim) Sawyer (12-14, 2/6/23) Dormitories: Parnall (12-2, plans for nurses home) Mooney (11-28, re: building dormitories privately) Murfin (11-29, 10/9,14,18,24,25/22, 11/1/22 and 3/15,19,20/23, 4/19/23) (See also Law School buildings). Early efforts: Associated Press clippings (1-8) Engineering building: M.E.Cooley (5-33, passim; 10-6, 10/11/22, 12/29/22) Funding and gifts: Clements (1-27; 5-29; 10-2, passim, re: Engineering, Hospital, and Museum buildings funding) Groesbeck (10-24, 10/14/22, Law School funding; 10/1/22, Literary building funding; 10/17, 19/19, and 11/23/22, payment procedures; 4/25/23, Minutes of State Administrative Board; 6/9/23, Nurses Home funding) Couzens (14-10 passim, re: donation for Nurses Home) Murfin (11-29, 11/7/22, funds for re-modeling gyms) (See also William Cook correspondence in folders labelled Coo-Cz) Hospital Building: Parnall (3-34 passim) S.W.Smith (4-15, passim, on costs) Vaughan (4-30, 10/9/20) Cabot (9-28, 5/4 and 5/17/23) Labor problems: Shepard (12-17, 2/28/23) Law School Buildings: Bates (1-11, passim; 5-11, 4/4/22; 9-17, passim; 13-14, 11/23 and 12/23/22, 5/8, 5/13 and 6/23/24; 17-18, 7/24, 8/1, 9/2, 9/13, 10/14, 11/1, 11/17 and 11/19/24) Clements (10-2, 8/11/22, acquisition of land) Hubbard (11-2, 11/6/22, 4/9/23, terms of Cook's gift) Kahn (11-10) York (13-4; 17-12) Cook (14-8; 18-1; also Cook correspondence in folders labelled Coo-Cz.) Michigan League (Not built until 1927): Alumnae Council (5-4, passim) Pomeroy (4-1; 7-30) Michigan League (15-20, on fund drive and plans) Organization: Christensen (13-29, 12/1, and 12/12/23, organization chart and duties of Building Committee, 12/29/23) Planning: Clements (1-27; 5-29; 10-2, passim) M.E.Cooley (10-6, 7/1/22, use of U-M architects in planning) Progress and Problems: Pardon (12-5, 8/23/22, 1/22/23; 15-31, passim) Christensen (13-29, 12/29/23, bulletins of progress) Groesbeck (10-24, 4/11/23; 14-27, 12/6/23, progress reports to governor) State relations: Groesbeck (6-14, 1/24/22, 3/10/22, 7/13/21, comprehensive reports to legislature; 7/13/21, 6/12/22; 10-24, 11/8/22, 3/3/23)
III. Academic units: Changes and additions Homeopathic School and Hospital General: Gore (2-13; 10-22, 8/21/22, 19-22) Hinsdale (2-21) Springer (4-17) Cabot (5-24,passim) Hanchett (6-7, 12/21) Murfin (7-17, 11/4/21, 12/2/21, 12/10/21, 1/9/22) Beal (13-15, 1/19/24) Groesbeck (6-14, 1/24/22, MLB memo of interview with governor) Sawyer (8-9, 12/15/21) Legislative resolution: S.W. Smith (8-15, memo containing text of resolution to consolidate) Letters in opposition to any change: Correspondence, (Baa-Baz 1-9, passim; Coa-Coz 1-28, Copeland letters; Da-Dn, 2-1,passim) Letters in support of plan: Homeopathic Medical School (2-22) Possibility of re-establishing Homeopathic School: Hubbard (11-2, 3/29/23, 4/25/23); Gore (14-25, 3/22 and 3/23/23) Reports and proposals: Hinsdale (6-21) and Homeopathic Medical School (6-22) include reports and resolution on consolidation. Springer (8-17, 5/8/22) Results: Parnall (7-25, 4/20/22; 12-2, 4/3/23; 15-32, 10/24/23, 11/10/23, 12/17/23, 12/29/23) Springer (8-17, 1/21/22) Statistics: Murfin (11-29, 4/17/23; 15-23, summary of costs in past 6 yrs.) Homeopathic Medical School (2-21, 9/20, editorial re: declining enrollment) Relation of University Hospital to Medical School General: Murfin (3-26, 4/2/21; 15-23, 3/12/24) Sawyer (8-9, 11/3/21; 12-14, 1/29/23, 5/22/23) Gore: 10-22, 12/27/22; 14-25, 2/18/24) Beal: (13-15, 11/10 and 11/28/23, 12/14/23, 1/9/24) Regents: (16-4, 2/14/24) Commission of Inquiry: Murfin (11-29, passim); Parnall (12-2, 10/20/22); Sawyer (12-14, 12/27/22, 3/7 and 5/17/23) Full-time professorships vs. Clinical practice salaries: Cabot (1-21; 5-24; 13-25, 10/25/23) Sawyer: (4-7, passim; 8-9, 5/2 and 5/5/22) Parnall (15-32, 11/7/23) University Hospital: (8-26, 2/28/21) Faculty resolution favoring Hospital under Medical School: Parnall (7-25, 11/20/21; MLB reply, 12/16/21) Funding: Groesbeck (10-24, 3/14/23) Vaughan (4-30, passim) New Hospital Director appointed: University Hospital - Directorship (16-26; 16-27) Sawyer (16-10, passim) Haynes (18-24, 8/27/24, 9/1/24, MLB letter outlining problems) Nursing School as separate school: Parnall (7-25, 6/24/22; 12-2, 9/23/22) Sawyer (12-14, 9/18, 9/23, and 10/21/22) Policy of separate Hospital and Medical School re- affirmed: Hubbard (15-2, 2/13/24) Regents (18-55, 8/1/24) Separate budgets for Medical School and Hospital: Sawyer (8-9, 4/18/22, undated MLB memo giving Regents position) Staff statement re: separation: Vaughan (4-30, 1/17/21) Treating indigent patients: Sawyer (4-7, passim) Cabot (9-28, passim) Groesbeck (10-24, 3/6/23) Resignation of Hospital superintendent: Parnall (15-32, 1/26 and 2/12/24) Stone (16-18, Jan/Feb '24) Architecture, Need to separate from School of Engineering: Hubbard (2-25, passim) Lorch (3-6, 12/3/20) Curriculum Changes: Effinger (14-19, Mar.'24, on Greek Department needs; 4/2/24 "University system" of seminar teaching) Dental School: Ward (17-4, 5/7/24) Dutch History Professorship Contribution Fund for Dutch history (14-16, 4/29/24) Effinger (14-19, 1/13, 1/21, and 1/31/24) Education, School of Establishment: S.W.Smith (4-14, passim; 4-15, 6/1/21, Text of Regents' resolution) Granting of teacher certificates: Whitney (9-4, 4/6/22) Effinger (6-3, 10/27/21, 1/27/22, Apr.'22) Organization of School: Whitney (4-35; 9-4) University High School: Whitney (12-39, 12/28/22, Proposed '23-'24 budget) Extension Services, Expansion of: Henderson (2-19, passim; 10-30, 2/27/23) Engineering Research, Department of General: Engineering Research (2-7) Hanchett (2-17, passim; 6-7, Apr.'22; 10-28, 6/11/23) Hutchins (2-28, 5/10/20) Iowa University (2-31, information on bills to permit federal funding) Lloyd (3-7, 7/20/20) Michigan Manufacturing Association (3-19, passim) S.W. Smith (4-15, 7/30/20, Regents resolution setting up Planning Committee) White (4-34, 7/7/20, aims of department and relation to manufacturers; 9-2; 12-38) Expansion of department: M.E. Cooley (5-33, 12/7/21) Outside work: Parker (7-26, 12/21/20, 2/15/21, 9/26/21, 5/15/22) M.E. Cooley (5-33, 2/3/22, 5/25/22; 10-6, 11/11/22) Patents: M.E. Cooley (18-3, 8/21/24, 10/10/24) Projects: M.E. Cooley (5-33, 1/22 and 1/25/22, evaporator work for sugar companies) Sawyer (8-9, 6/13/22, use of results of studies) White (all folders include material on research projects and problems) Reports: White (9-2; 12-38, passim) M.E. Cooley (14-9, 7/3 and 8/20/23) Riggs (8-5; 12-11; 16-5; 19-2, all include annual reports on State Highway Laboratory work) Salaries and appointments: M.E. Cooley (14-9, 12/29/23, 1/13/24, Feb.'24) Fellowship in Creative Art: Establishment of Program: Hughes(2-27) Effinger (6-3, 4/6 and 4/19/22) Lloyd (7-7, 4/6/22) Frost, Robert (Holder of Fellowship, first two years): Bursley (5-21, 7/9/21, living arrangements for Frost) Frost (6-10; 10-18) Regents (8-4, 7/20/21, Frost's acceptance letter) Funding: Osborn (7-22, July-Sept '21 re: his gift to start program; 6/12, 6/14, and 6/17/22; 11-33, 7/1 and 7/17/22, further fund-raising proposals) Regents (12-9, 6/21 and 6/25/23; 18-55, 6/27/24, proposal for Rackham funding for '24-'25 program) Other candidates: M.E. Cooley (10-6, 7/7/22, proposes painter Gerrit Beneker) Beal (13-15, 6/29/23 and 7/28/23, suggests major English writers) Bridges, Robert (held Fellowship, April-June 1924) (13-19) Creative Art Fellowship (14-11, candidates for '24-'25; 18-5, attempts to find appointee for that year) Effinger (14-19, 7/17/23) Burton (17-25 passim, efforts to get '24-'25 candidates, including suitable women) Robbins 19-4, 8/14 and 8/25/24, candidates Percy Hammond and J.L. Williams) Hygiene and Public Health, Department of Sundvall (4-22, Sept.'21) Hubbard (6-26, 10/6/21) Murfin (7-17, 10/17 and 10/24/21) Library Science, Department of Bishop (9-20, 12/30/22) Music School: Effinger (2-4 passim) Gore (10-22, passim) Physical Education, Department of Murfin (3/26, passim) Rowe (4-5) Athletic Association (5-7, passim) Hubbard (6-26, 10/6/21) Whitney (9-4, 11/22/21, Feb.'22) Social Work, Establishment of curriculum in Effinger (2-4, passim) Social workers (4-16) Murfin (3-26, 10/8/20) University Health Service Sundvall (8-20, 10/28 and 12/8/21; 12-24, passim) Forsythe (2-11) Hanchett (6-7, Dec.'21)
IV. Miscellaneous Retirement pay: Carnegie Foundation (1-23, passim; 5-26, 5/12/22; 13-26, 11/15/23, 12/7 and 12/17/23 on eligibility rules, 1/17/24 on relation to TIAA plan) Henderson (6-18, 3/18/22, 5/16/22, on ineligibility of administrative officers) S.W. Smith (8-15, 11/3 and 11/10/21) Ward (4-32, 12/21/20, on securing retirement pay for dental faculty) M.E. Cooley (14-9, 12/4/23, eligibility of three Engineering professors) Women's issues Hamilton (10-27, 8/8/22 on standards for women's education, 3/12/23, Barbour Gym and Michigan League; 14-30, 6/20/24, problems posed by lack of university controlled dorms; 18-21, 9/27/24 on lack of women on faculty) Beal (17-19, 10/21/24 on operation of Helen Newberry Residence) Smith (19-9, 8/9, 8/14, and 8/15/24 on George Herbert Palmer gift for a professorship to be held by a woman) Stone (19-11, 8/28/24 on Palmer proposal) Pomeroy (4-1, passim, on physical education planning) Cabot (13-25, 3/18, 4/2 and 5/24/24 re: Barbour Scholarship for Oriental Women) Effinger (14-19, 3/20/24, reply to Cabot) Student Christian Association Coffman (14-4; 17-34, includes annual reports of general secretary of SCA) Hopkins (6-25, on clearing debt of SCA) International Committee (6-29, 1/14 and 2/28/22)